Ryan Mitchell

Senior Software Engineer at HedgeServ

Summary

I'm a speaker (Data Day Seattle and Texas, DEFCON, various Boston-area meetup groups), educator, and runner of workshops about web scraping, web security, and data science.

Author of two books: Instant Web Scraping with Java (Packt Publishing, https://www.packtpub.com/web-development/instant-web-scraping-java-instant) and Web Scraping with Python (O'Reilly, June 2015, http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920034391.do) The second edition of WSwP is planned for release in early 2018.

I've worked full time as a software engineer (with occasional forays into UX and "Solutions Architecture" -whatever that is) since graduating from Olin College of Engineering. While working, I spent four years getting
my masters in software engineering and still like to keep in touch with academia on the side. I'm currently
doing some consulting with Northeastern on their software engineering course offerings, including major
course redesigns, and plan on teaching a full stack web application development course in the fall of 2018.
I also taught a data science course at Olin College of Engineering (Fall 2017) a web development course for
adult education at the Boston Public Library (Spring 2017).

In addition to teaching adults, I teach proto-adults (also known as "children") as a volunteer for the Tech Studio/ Engineering department at the Museum of Science on Sunday afternoons.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer at HedgeServ

June 2016 - Present

I create analytics tools for hedge fund managers. The 5 person (3 dev, 1 lead, 1 QA) team in the Boston satellite office is responsible for maintaining ~12 applications, as well as new application and infrastructure development.

Languages: Java, Python (2 and 3), Node, occasional Ember and Angular.

Databases: Redis, Mongo, GraphQL, SQL Server

A handful of other technologies and languages on top of that. Our stack was built over many years...

Software Engineer at LinkeDrive, Inc

November 2013 - May 2016 (2 years 7 months)

I develop REST APIs and data models for terabytes of raw data coming off of truck engines. Who wants to see what the fuel rate was during a particular millisecond of engine operation? Nobody. But everybody wants

to see at a glance if a driver has been performing better over the past week, or if the fleet's meeting target goals! So that's what I do.

There's a lot of Java and giant AWS cloud services involved

Solutions Architect at Velir

December 2012 - October 2013 (11 months)

Technical liaison between clients and developers for large, high-budget web projects, including Bayer CropScience and Population Reference Bureau. Drove client meetings, identified risks, and worked across all departments to turn proposed designs into working products.

Sitecore certified

Software Engineer at Abine, Inc.

January 2012 - December 2012 (1 year)

I work primarily on Abine's DeleteMe service, which removes people from the "white pages" of the internet -- sites like Spokeo, PeopleFinders, Intelius, etc.

I develop and maintain their Drupal e-commerce site, write web crawlers for these (often crawler-resistant) sites, design and develop automation processes to increase efficiency, and work with DeleteMe operators and customer feedback to improve the product.

Work mostly with Python, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, and a smattering of other technologies

User Experience Architect at Mobiquity Inc.

May 2011 - December 2011 (8 months)

Web Application Developer at Harvard University

June 2009 - August 2010 (1 year 3 months)

Technology Intern at MITRE

2008 - 2008 (1 year)

Intern

2007 - 2007 (1 year)

Intern at Microsoft

2006 - 2006 (1 year)

Research Labs Intern at Sun Microsystems

2005 - 2005 (1 year)

Education

Harvard Extension School

Masters in Information Technology, Computer Software Engineering

Franklin W. Olin College of Engineering

Bachelors, General Engineering

Activities and Societies: Editor in Chief of Frankly Speaking (college newspaper), President of the Judaism at

Olin Organization, President of the Ham Radio Club.

Phillips Academy

Summer Program

Activities and Societies: Introduction to Java, Discrete Math

Pierce College

Associate of Science - AS, Science

Activities and Societies: Journalist and A&E Editor of the Pierce Pioneer (student newspaper)

Sumner High School

Degree: N/A

Activities and Societies: None. I was a punk.

Ryan Mitchell

Senior Software Engineer at HedgeServ



Contact Ryan on LinkedIn